{
    "id": "e390acf35e6b4d83a8da44e57a15474f",
    "title": "Common Structures In English",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "8f3e195978b7463fbed833749fb063db",
            "title": "Common English Structures",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I would rather consult a doctor than ................................ in fear.",
                    "description": "Would rather is followed by an infinitive without to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "live",
                        "to live",
                        "living"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I can't help ................................... about her.",
                    "description": "If you say that you can’t help doing something, you mean that you can’t stop yourself from doing it. \r\nIn this structure we use an ing form after help.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "to worry",
                        "worrying",
                        "worry"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I couldn't help ................................... those cookies.",
                    "description": "If you say that you can’t help doing something, you mean that you can’t stop yourself from doing it. \r\nIn this structure we use an ing form after help.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "eating",
                        "to eat"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is busy ................................. ready for work.",
                    "description": "The structure I am busy is followed by an –ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to get",
                        "getting",
                        "with getting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am busy .................................... the house.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "to clean",
                        "cleaning",
                        "to cleaning"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Brother is busy ...................................... his studies.",
                    "description": "Instead of an –ing form, we can use with + noun after I’m busy.",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "from",
                        "of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am looking forward .................................. Paris.",
                    "description": "Look forward to / Looking forward to is followed by an ing form or a noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to visit",
                        "visiting",
                        "to visiting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will help you ....................................... the cleaning.",
                    "description": "Before a noun we use help with.",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "about",
                        "to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Can you help me ....................................... my keys?",
                    "description": "Help can be followed by object + infinitive with or without to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "find",
                        "to find",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is your turn .................................... the dishes.",
                    "description": "An infinitive with to is used in this structure.",
                    "answers": [
                        "doing",
                        "to do",
                        "to doing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am having a hard time ..................................... a good job.",
                    "description": "An ing form is used in this structure.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to find",
                        "finding",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You had better ..................................... me my money back.",
                    "description": "After had better the infinitive is used without to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to give",
                        "give",
                        "to giving"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}